## **Amit Kumar**

Email address: amitaec94@gmail.com

Mob no: +91-8951972209

Nationality: Indian my Linked in profile

## Summary

Experiences in Object Oriented Analysis, Design and Development, Agile Framework, Web API,
Rest/Micro bases Services, Html, CSS, & javaScript. Analyzing user requirement envisioning system
feature functionality.
Developing Application using SQL DATABASES ,Schema, SQL Queries and also familiar with GIT and
Version Control system, Skilled in data SQL server or Oracle, SQL Queries, Query Optimization.
Experience in developing Web/Enterprise based applications using Java/J2EE, Spring MVC.
Excellent Communication and Verbal Skills.
Strong in Analytical, Logical Skills and Team Leading Skills

3.9 years of IT experience in development of web-based applications as well as core java application.

- Contributing to team Meetings, Troubleshooting development and production problem across multiple environments
- □ Ability to effectively self-manage during independent projects as well as collaborate as part of a productive team.
- Possess strong functional & result -oriented skills and commitment to work with good learning attitude. Can easily adapt to any technology and tools and learn them very quickly.

## **Technical Skills**

Operating Systems	Windows 10 & Linux
Languages	Java 7 and 8
Web Technology	HTML, CSS, JavaScript
Frameworks	Spring 4.X, Angular 7
ORM Technology	JPA
Web Services	REST & Microservices
Databases	Oracle SQL Developer
Application Server	Web Logic 10.3.6, JBOSS EAP 6 and 7
Continuous Integration tool	Jenkins Build tool
Code coverage	Sonar code coverage tool
Versioning Tools	Bit bucket
Mocking Framework	Power-Mockito 1.7

## **Professional Experience**

Currently Working as Associate (FSE) at Cognizant Technology Solution from 26-May-2016 to till date.

**Highlight**: Currently working on **ELK Implementation** on AWS console and Triggering an Error mail Notification system. Engineer with strong experience in setting up for large volume of Business data.

### Cognizant Technology Solution Experience

<u>Project 1</u>: IPLUS (Incentive Cash Offering)

**Duration** : Sep 2019 to Till date

Team Size : 8

### Responsibilities:

Member of Scrum team in an agile environment with life-cycle of 9 days per Sprint, Closely working with testers and the product Owner.
 Enhanced and Optimized logistics management services.
 Actively involved in developing complex modules and common services.
 Developed and present findings & solutions to the product owners.
 Worked to solve problem using the latest in cloud technologies( ELK)
 Documented all enhancement in confluence for future references.

**Environment/tools:** Spring boot 2.0.4, Maven 3+, Oracle SQL Developer 4.1.3, JDK 1.8, Jboss, Jenkins, Winscp, putty, Jfrog, Bitbucket, Kinesis Agent, aws, Elastic search.

#### Project 2:

**Project** : IPLUS (Reorg Legacy Code and Integrated With DevOps for Continuous Integration)

**Duration**: May 2019 to Sep 2019

Team Size : 3

#### Responsibilities:

	IPLUS Bit bucket repo should be work independently based on <b>microservice architecture</b>
	During separation of each repo , bit bucket history should be maintained
	Each domain repo should able to pass all Jenkins stages and publish that jar to jfrog repo
	Used JIRA to report and fix the Defects for the application.
	Worked closely with the DevOps team and other team members to form a team effort in
	development when have dependencies.
П	Documented all modification in confluence as well for future references.

**Environment/tools:** Spring Maven 3.5+, Oracle SQL Developer 4.1.3, JDK 1.8, Jboss, Jenkins, Winscp, putty, Jfrog .

#### Project 3:

**Project** : IPLUS (JBOSS Migration 6.x to 7.x)

**Duration**: Jan 2019 to Mar 2019

Team Size : 2

#### Responsibilities:

- □ Configured domain.xml configuration file for all environment
- ☐ Identified and merge all queues into configuration file
- □ Updated socket binding configuration

	MQ and changed OLTP connection for all environment additions updated in JIRA as well as Confluence.			
Project 4				
Project	: Incentive Plus(IPLUS)			
Duration	: Dec 2018 to July 2018			
Team Size	<b>:</b> 9			
<ul> <li>Developed and implemented Web applications using Java/J2EE Technologies including Core Java, JDBC, Spring and JPA.</li> <li>Involved in analysis, and design in development Under <b>Agile</b> methodology</li> <li>Involved in creating the project war, executable jar file and deploy in Web Logic server.</li> <li>Used JIRA to report and fix the Defects for the application.</li> <li>Also implemented UI Functionality with the help of angular 7</li> <li>Integrated with sonar to fix critical or major issues.</li> </ul>				
<u>Project 5</u>				
Project	: NAPO DS			
Duration	: Dec 2017 to July 2018			
Team Size	: 8			
Responsibilities:				
<ul> <li>Developing and implementing Web applications using Java/J2EE Technologies including Core Java, JDBC, Spring and Hibernate.</li> <li>Involved in analysis, and design in development Under <b>Agile</b> methodology</li> <li>Involved in creating the project war, executable jar file and deploy in Web Logic server.</li> <li>Developed and debugged the application using Eclipse IDE</li> <li>Used JIRA to report and fix the Defects for the application.</li> <li>Worked closely with project managers and other team members to form a team effort in development when have dependencies.</li> <li>Prepared in Junit Test Cases Using Power Mockito and achieved 90%+code coverage</li> <li>Integrated sonar + corbetura to track coverage and issue.</li> </ul>				
Education				
Asansol engir	neering college, Maulana Abul Kalam Azad University of Technology West Bengal.			
Degree: B.tech- Electronics & Instrumentation.				
Passing year:	2015.			
Personal de	etails			
Date of birth: 27 <sup>h</sup> feb 1994 Gender: Male Marital status: Unmarried				

# Pe

Father's Name: Hari Shankar Prasad

Language: Hindi, English.

# Interest

Travelling, Gaming, Movies.

(Amit Kumar) Place: CHENNAI